what's up guys and girls in this video I'm going to show you the basics of how to use the controllers that you have in your hands
if you look down at them you'll see that they have six buttons each you'll use three fingers to control these buttons your index finger will control the button in front it's called the trigger look down at this button and press it a couple of times with your index finger to get used to the feel of it to select something you point with your controller and press the figure or if you're in a shooting game the trigger is what you use to fire
extend your hand in front of you like your holding a gun
and press the trigger button a few times to get used to the movement now look at the side of the controller and you'll see a button called the grip button your second finger which is the middle finger is used to press it hold your controller like this and press the grip a few times to get used to it this button is used to pick up and hold things in virtual reality
you can grab a gun grab a sword grab anything you want and hold on to it by keeping the grip button pressed
your ring finger and your little finger will be used to hold on to the controller
now look at the top of the controller
and you'll see a thumb stick button
what you might call a joystick
put your thumb on it and move it around a bit
push it forward and back
side to side
these joysticks are used to move around within virtual reality or scroll through menu options
you can also press it down like a button try using the thumb stick now
next is the A and B buttons on your right controller and your X and Y buttons on the left controller each of these buttons has different uses in different games your instructor will show you how to use them within the games you choose to play press these buttons a few times to understand how they feel
finally you have your menu buttons which are the really small ones on the bottom of the controller
movie.com or what these buttons and Friends them now
wherever you are in virtual reality the right button will take you to the main menu where you can change the game you're playing or Share Cast or record your screen the left menu button is the sub menu and it will take you to the sub menu of any game of your playing when you press it so to quickly recap and follow along with me use your first finger for the trigger
second finger or middle finger for the grip
your thumb for the joystick or thumbstick and for the A and B buttons and your menu buttons
your little finger and ring finger will be used to hold on to the controller